hey Zed hey how are you doing today
great are you free to answer some
questions
[Music]
sure in one word how would you describe
2023 for investors interesting how so
interesting because most asset classes
in general had a great year and 2022 was
not a great year so this was a great
recovery and if our clients were
Diversified in 2023 they were definitely
happy can you explain why Global
Securities had a great year in general
Global equities and fixed income both
benefited from the positive sentiment on
inflation as inflation continued to
moderate during the year investors
became more and more confident that rate
Cuts were just around the corner and
mindful of the fact that a lower
interest rate environment is positive
for Global equities and fixed income
furthermore Global equities benefited
from the excitement on the long-term
benefits of developments in artificial
intelligence or AI for particularly on
companies Revenue monetization
productivity and cost cutting what about
local Securities unfortunately for
Philippine equities they didn't have the
sort of party that Global equities
generally had in 2023 persistent High
inflation in the first part of the Year
followed by moderating inflation in the
fourth quarter meant that the PSI was
basically flat year on year Philippine
fixed income had a better story with
local interest rates falling during the
year as inflation continued to moderate
consider considering the great year for
Global Securities I'm curious about our
Global funds can you give us an overview
of how some of them
performed us growth did around 30 to
31% Global Market leaders did around 19
to
20% despite of the fact that it did not
have a full year of performance because
it was only launched last year and
Global multi asset income or jimai did
10 to
11% including impact of payouts these
three funds benefited from what I
mentioned earlier excitement over
moderating inflation and AI for
Philippine Securities fixed income did
well with peso cash fund doing around
5% net returns that's very informative
Zed I think we have a lot to look
forward to this 2024 yes glob and
locally the key is whether inflation
will continue to fall in a sustained
manner as this will impact when rate
Cuts will happen which will then mean
more positive sentiment with this do you
think it's a good year for customers to
start or continue
investing while it is still uncertain
when the rate Cuts will happen consensus
is that they will happen in 2024 and as
long as our clients are Diversified and
not just invested in one country or one
asset class we believe there is room to
be optimistic for 2024 for those who
would like to plan for retirement there
is indeed reason to be happy we recently
launched future boost retirement this is
a powerful solution to go beyond savings
and pension for their retirement by
combining the benefits of life insurance
with potential for wealth accumulation
through expertly managed funds in
addition AS Global and local economies
continue to evolve future boost
retirement can help protect them in the
present while preparing for a
comfortable retirement the automatic
fund allocation feature allows their
funds to be allocated in Diversified
Global Equity Funds in the early years
with higher potential for growth but as
they get older and approach their
retirement age their funds will
automatically be invested in safer
assets for preservation this is great
let's help our customers retire ready in
life